だとすると、滝沢の携帯は
何でもできる魔法の携帯ってことか？
You mean Takizawa has a magic cell phone that can do anything?
ダメ。通りに出て捕まえよう！
It's hopeless.
Let's try to hail a taxi on the street.
Anyway, in the meantime, go through the data Pants sent.
とにかく、まずはパンツの送ったデータ調べてみて
I couldn't get a hold of him.
あいつとも連絡とれないの
分かった、やってみる。
だがお前たちは豊洲に来るなっ
Got it. I'll try.
You two shouldn't come to Toyosu, though.
Why?
なんでよ？
実はな、
To be honest, the missing NEETs have broken into the cinema in search of Takizawa.
行方不明だったニートたちが
滝沢を探してシネコンになだれ込んできたんだ
It's the end for this place.
ここはもう、お終いだ
We'll kill you, Takizawa Akira!
Episode 11
The East Goes On Further
よく知ってたわね、こんなところ
Good thing you knew about this place.
不動産資料を見ていたときにな
I found it when I was looking at the information from the real estate agent.
だいじょぶか？ こんなところに隠れて
Will we be safe hiding here?
どのみち、イカレル全裸オトコに道理は通じませんよ！
Whatever happens, it's impossible to reason with those angry, naked men.
寒いのに、行儀よく携帯を回収してるわ
Even though it's cold, they're searching for their cell phones in an orderly fashion.
何よりもまずは携帯というわけか
They think that retrieving their cell phones is most important?
もしもし？
Hello?
あ、一臣？
Kazuomi?
やっぱりそっちに行くよ。
一緒にデータ調べたほうが早いと思うから
We'll still be heading there after all.
I think it'll be faster if we go through the data together.
そうか
I see.
しかし、60発のミサイル攻撃は本当にあるのか？
But are sixty missiles really going to be launched?
それにあったとして、今から俺たちに何ができる？
And if that does happen, what can we do now?
俺たちは魔法の携帯を持っているわけではないからな
After all, we don't have any magical cell phones with us.
滝沢くんは、
魔法の携帯を持ってたから住民を助けたんじゃないと思う
I don't think that Takizawa-kun is saving the citizens just because he has a magical cell phone.
He's just doing what he thinks is the right thing to do.
ただ、当たり前のことをしようとしただけなんだよ
Then why did he erase his own memories?
じゃあ、なぜ奴は自ら記憶を消したりした？
And why are so many NEETs angry at him?
あの大量のニートはなぜ滝沢に怒っているんだ？
そうだよ、咲ちゃん！
That's right, Saki-chan.
でなかったら、
あいつらだってあんなに怒りゃしないって！
He must've done something, or they wouldn't be so angry at him.
Oosugi-kun, Takizawa-kun didn't just protect the citizens.
大杉くん、
滝沢くんはミサイルから住民を守っただけじゃなくて、
避難誘導に手を貸したことで疑惑の目を向けられた
二万人のニートを守るために、
20,000 NEETs helped out with the evacuation, and people were pretty suspicious of them.
一人で悪者になって記憶を消したんだよ
To protect those NEETs, he took sole responsibility and erased his memories.
滝沢くんはあの携帯を受け取ったあと、
Right after he received the phone, he gathered volunteers based on information available on the net.
ネット上で得た情報を元に有志を集め、
He saved the people using methods that bordered on the illegal.
犯罪行為すれすれの方法で
住民を逃がすことに成功したの
それがあの二万人ということか？
Those 20,000 NEETs were volunteers?
Yes. I think so.
うん、だと思う
だけど、助けられた住民は、
その後メディアを通して不満を漏らし始めた
However, after they were saved, the citizens started to voice their discontent to the media.
滝沢くんたちはミサイルが落ちることをなぜ知っていたのか？
They wanted to know why Takizawa-kun and the volunteers knew about the missile attacks.
本当は別の目的があったんじゃないのかって
People claimed the volunteers had their own objectives, or made similar comments.
滝沢くんたちも実際にミサイルが
落ちてくるかは分からなかったから、
In reality, Takizawa-kun and the volunteers didn't know the reason behind the missile attack either,
中には現場で盗みを働いたりした人もいたらしいの
and some of them looted around the attack sites.
それでも、大半の人は
住民を救ったという事実に燃えていた
Even so, most of them were excited that they were able to save the people.
けど、ミサイルですべてを失った住民は、
However, the people who'd lost everything due to the missiles
were unable to suppress suspicions that appeared in their hearts.
一度芽生えてしまった疑いの心を
抑えることができなかった
すると今度は、事態を傍観していた人たちが、
避難住民をネットを使って誹謗中傷し始めた
After that, people who'd just observed the incidents started flaming on the net about those who'd escaped.
それがあの事件を、
より複雑かつ奇妙なものに変えてしまった原因のひとつなの
That was one reason the whole matter got more complicated and strange.
滝沢くんはそこで、
いくつかの偽名を使って彼らを豊洲に集めると、
At that point, Takizawa used various aliases to gather the NEETs in Toyosu.
He claimed he was responsible for the missile attacks, in order to make them focus their anger solely on him.
怒りの矛先を自分ひとりに向けさせるために、
自分がミサイルテロの犯人だと名乗った
滝沢くんを複数の名前で認識していたり、
怒りをあらわにしているのは、それが理由だと思う
I think that's why people know him by various names, and why they are so angry with him.
そのあと滝沢くんは、彼らを世間の目から隠すために、
３ヶ月間ドバイに逃がした
After that, he sent them to Dubai for three months to shield them from public view.
不確かな情報や、自分にとって都合のいい噂で
The majority of the people were irresponsible,
簡単に自分の意見を変えてしまう無責任な大多数
easily changing their views based on unverified information and self-serving rumors.
Takizawa-kun was betrayed by the people he wanted to protect the most.
滝沢くんは一番守りたかった人たちに裏切られ、
He felt hopeless, so he had no choice but to erase his own memories.
絶望し、それで記憶を消すしかなかったんだよ
奴はそのことを思い出したのか？
Does he remember all of that?
I don't know.
分からない
But this time, we must figure out a way to deal with the upcoming missile attack by ourselves.
でも今度は
私たちだけでミサイル攻撃をなんとかしなくちゃならないの
なんで咲ちゃんがそんな風に思う必要があるんだ！
Saki-chan, why are you thinking like that?!
Even if Takizawa really is a good man, isn't he just an idiot?
滝沢が本当にいい奴だったとして、
でもあいつはただのバカじゃないか！
With such an amazing cell phone, he did something so foolish.
そんな携帯持ってて下手こいてるなんて、
ただのバカとしか思えないよ！
I can't see him as anything more than an idiot!
The data from Itazu-kun should show the missile targets.
板津くんのデータに、
ミサイルの落ちるところも記録されていると思うの
If we release that information onto the Internet like Takizawa-kun did on Careless Monday...
迂闊な月曜日のときに滝沢くんがやったように、
ネットにそのことを書き込めば
確かにな。殺人予告一行で逮捕者が出るご時世だ
That might work.
These days, people get arrested for just writing a single line saying that they'll kill someone.
ミサイル攻撃があるって書けば、
If we wrote that a missile attacking is incoming, there should be some sort of reaction.
何らかのリアクションは起こせるだろう
ただ…
However...
What do you mean, "however"?
ただ、何よ？
The current situation doesn't allow us to do that.
事態はそれを許さぬ状況にある
どういうこと？
Why?
Itazu's data is in the hands of those zombies now!
板津のデータは今、ゾンビの手の中だからだっ！
すみません、先輩のPC、バーに置いてきてしまいましたっ！
Sorry!
If you know what I mean...
A dying scream makes no sound
We live a dying dream...
It's all that I've ever known
I left Hirasawa's PC in the bar!
It's all that I've ever known...
Callin' out to all that I've ever known
Catch the wheel that breaks a butterfly
あった、これです！
http://animetranscripts.wikispaces.com
Calling him up in-and-out of nowhere
I tried to talk with God to no avail
Cry the rain that fills the ocean wide
Found it!
Here am I, lost and found...
Over there.
Eh? Where?
ええっ、どこ？
ここ。この男が抱えてます
Over here. He's holding onto it.
I said if you won't save me
Callin' out to all
Please don't waste my time
しかし、どうやって回収する？
How are we going to get it back?
Requesting permission to speak!
進言します！ ここは攻めに転じる意味でも、
全裸になってみてはいかがでしょうか！？
This would mean that we'll need to be on the offensive, but why don't we go naked?!
なぜ全裸なのだ？
Why do we need to go naked?
Sir! You hide a tree in a forest.
木を隠すなら森、
In order to blend in with the naked NEETs, the best strategy is to go naked!
裸のニートにまぎれるなら、
こちらも裸になるのが得策かとっ！
えー、ムリムリムリ…
No way! No, no, no!
気づかれませんね。作戦は大成功です
They haven't noticed us.
The strategy is a great success.
Seems so...
のようだな
早く来い！ ここまで来て何をためらう！
Hurry up and get over here!
Why are you hesitating when we've come this far?
いや、そうなんだけどさ…
Well, even so...
ま、マジ？！
I-Is this for real?!
We have to meet up with
Hirasawa-kun and the rest, or we'll...
何とか平澤くんたちと合流しないと…
サッと駆け抜ければ、案外大丈夫かも
Surprising them might work, if we just make a dash for it.
女子だーっ！
Women!
PCですか
Is that a PC?
ええ、でもパスワードが掛かっていて
Yeah, but it's password protected.
ちょっと貸してみてください
Let me take a look at it.
もまいら、毛あるな。やけに白いし
You guys have hair and are awfully pale...
では失礼…
Excuse me.
逃げろー！
Run!
付いて来てる…
They're catching up...
Don't worry, they're probably only interested in 2D.
大丈夫
あの人たち、たぶん二次元にしか興味ないから
Oosugi! Catch!
大杉、パス！
先輩…
Oosugi!
大杉！ そのまま行けっ！
Oosugi, keep running!
さ、咲ちゃん…
S-Saki-chan...
お…大杉くん、なんで裸なのっ！
Oosugi-kun, why are you naked?!
Don't put it there!
そんなところに当てないで！
何すんだよ、せっかく取り戻してきたのにィ！
What the hell are you doing?! It took me a lot of effort to get that back!
ごめん！ でも今は板津くんのデータを…！
Sorry, but Itazu-kun's data comes first...
This way! Hurry up and come in!
こっちよ！ 早く中に！
Sis!
おネエ！
Wasn't the trip here difficult?
よーく来られたわねえ！
You can celebrate later. Quick, check the data!
それより、早くデータを！
確か、赤文字のところがあったと思うけど
If I remember correctly, there was some stuff here marked in red.
これ？
This?
Make the sender have the name of MP Yamamoto's lover, missile "
Hack surveillance satellite image
Induce preemptive attack
Hack Tomahawk missiles
deployed to cruiser
Planned for:
Fire 60 Tomahawk missiles
Hack Tomahawk missiles
Roppongi
The Diet
building
The bureaucracy
Targets:
国会や霞ヶ関も入ってるわ！
Even the National Diet and Kasumigaseki...
手分けしよう。まずは俺たちの携帯に送って
Let's split the work among us.
Send the data to our cell phones first.
分かった
Got it.
待って！ ウソ…これ見て！
Wait!
No way... Take a look at this!
Ikebukuro
Toyosu
Gunma
豊洲？！
Toyosu?!
な、何？
W-What happened?
あ、テステス。ただいまカメラの試験中
Testing. Testing.
I'm testing the camera now.
It's Takizawa!
滝沢だ！
Hi, Johnny!
ハーイ、ジョニー！
今日、もまいらをここに集めたのには訳がありまつ！
There's a reason why I gathered you guys here today!
I'm going to launch a new missile attack to eliminate you guys, because you know the truth about Careless Monday,
それは、迂闊な月曜日の真相を知っているもまいらと
俺を訴えようとした住民を
新たなミサイル攻撃で亡き者にするためなのでつ！
and the people who wanted to sue me as well!
ウソだよ！ なに言ってるの滝沢くん！
That's a lie!
What are you saying, Takizawa-kun!
滝沢くんがそんなことするはずないよ！
There's no way you'd do that!
Why are you lying?!
なんでそんなウソ言うの？！
これはウソではありません
I'm not lying.
ただし、生き延びるチャンスは無きにしも非ず！
However, I'm merciful enough to give you a chance to survive.
Those Johnnies who want to survive should gather on the roof!
まず、生き延びたいジョニーは屋上に集まるように！
滝沢くん…
Takizawa-kun...
ひどいですよ！
This is bad!
So far, we only know that we haven't captured Juiz.
今さらジュイスは手に入らないなんて！
すまないが、あとは自己責任ってことで
Sorry, but you've got to take responsibility for your own actions.
However, I intend to search for Mr. Outside again.
ただ、私はもう一度、
ミスター・アウトサイドを探すつもりだ
We'll meet again once I've managed to find him.
もし彼を見つけ出すことができたら、その時はまた会おう
そんな…
Why...
君、嵌められたんだよ
You were tricked.
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
やりすぎちゃったってことかな
You might have gone too far.
あの人がサポーターだったとしたら、どう？
What if he was the Supporter?
You launched the eleventh missile based on Mononobe-san's instruction, right?
11発目は物部さんに指示されたんでしょ？
He told you that it's better to eliminate the NEET witnesses or something along those lines, didn't he?
事件の生き証人であるニートは
消した方がいいとか言われてさ
ご愁傷さま。しかし、ナンバー９はおもろいねー
My condolences.
But No. 9 sure was interesting.
He'll probably do something this time as well.
たぶん今度も何かやらかすぜ
Nothing can be done now!
今からじゃ何もできないよ！
Didn't you hear that the strategic program for the Patriot missile defense system was rewritten two days ago?
おととい、パトリオットの戦略上のプログラムが
書き換えられたってニュース、聞かなかった？
You guys should escape without us first.
お前たちだけでも、先に脱出しろ！
それができないの！ 防火シャッター下りてて
We can't escape.
The rolling fire doors have been lowered...
あれで外に行けない？
Can't we head outside using that?
おえぇ！
無理だって！
It's impossible!
大杉くん！
Oosugi-kun!
Y-You're...!
おまえー！
滝沢？！
Takizawa?!
You're Oosugi?
お前が大杉？
ガッツあるな。想像してた通りだ
You've got guts. Just like I thought you would.
あの野郎！ 待ちやがれー！
待って、滝沢くん！
Wait, Takizawa-kun!
Takizawa-kun, you actually came here to save everyone, right?
滝沢くん、本当はみんなを助けに来たんでしょ？
また一人で悪者になって、それでみんなを…！
You're going to take all the blame again to save everyone.
You heard everything on the phone till the very end?
最後まで電話、聞いててくれたんだ
うん。でも、電池が切れちゃって
Yes, but my battery ran out...
あの後、板津のところに戻ったら、
平澤に履歴を送ったって言うんだ
I went to Itazu's place after that.
He said that he had sent the logs to Hirasawa.
で、あれを読んだら咲たち、
ぜってーここに来ちゃうと思って
I figured you guys would definitely come here after reading them.
滝沢くん、記憶は…？
Takizawa-kun, your memory...
You guys!
もまいら、よく戻ったな！
You came back safely!
だが、もうすぐミサイルが飛んでくるぞ
However, missiles will come flying at us soon!
今回は、直接ミサイルを撃ち落とす方法を
東のエデンサイトに書き込むのでつ！
This time, I want you guys to post the best way to bring a missile down directly on the Eden of the East website.
平澤さん…！
Hirasawa-san...
They have amazing potential if we get them to work together.
あいつらは直列に繋いでやれば
結構なポテンシャルを発揮するんだ
Together, we'll definitely make a miracle happen, just like on Careless Monday.
きっと、迂闊な月曜日のときのようにスッゲー奇跡を思いつく
After all, it's not something I can do alone.
元々、俺一人でやったわけじゃないんだよ
New                         Mail
Mail's here
もまいら！ うｐ乙～！
You guys, thanks for uploading!
We didn't upload anything.
うｐとかじゃねえし
ジュイス
Juiz?
Yes, this is Juiz.
はい、ジュイスです
Based on the posts on Eden of the East, the best way to evade the missile attack has been selected.
東のエデンの書き込みの中から
ミサイル攻撃回避に最適な方法を抽出いたしました
Please continue your work as a Savior who saves the country.
今後もこの国の救世主たらんことを
Thanks.
ありがとう。じゃあ、始めようか
Shall we begin?
バン！
Are you okay?
無事だったか？
Did Takizawa just do that?
これは…滝沢が起こしているのか？
ああ。そして、ここにいるニートたちによってな
Yeah, and he did it by using the NEETs here.
これが今、日本中で起きてるの？
Is this taking place all over Japan?
私のことはいつ助けに来てくれるの、ナンバー９？
When will you come and save me, No. 9?
I finally did something great...
やりよるのお、わし
I did it.
ミサイルなんか落ちなくたって、
Even though the missile launch failed, the country is still headed towards its doom.
この国は既に死に向かっている
とりあえず、間に合ったようだな
Looks like he made it on time.
バン！
I'm the Sundance Kid...?
サンダース・キッドかよ、俺は…
咲！
Saki!
ジュイス
Juiz.
What is it?
何でしょう？
We can't cover up this incident by having me take on the role of a terrorist.
今回は、テロリストを演じるだけじゃ
この事態をかばいきれないんだ
だから、残りのお金で俺をこの国の王様にしてくんない？
So, can you make me the king of this country with the remaining money I have?
King...?
王様…ですか？
ああ
Yes.
There are lots of smart people in this country.
この国には頭のいい連中がいっぱいいんのに、
No one is willing to do anything that puts them at a disadvantage though.
損な役回りやる奴がいないんだ
できれば、俺だってあんましやりたくはないけどさ、
I don't want to do it either, if possible.
But there's a girl that believed in me.
一人だけ信じてくれた子がいたから
受理されました。ノブレス・オブリージュ
Request accepted.
Noblesse Oblige.
May you become a wonderful prince the next time we meet.
今度会うときは、素敵な王子様たらんことを
そんときもこのままの俺でいたいよね
I hope that I remain myself when that moment arrives.
それとさ、ジュイス
Also, Juiz...
ちぇっ。このメリーゴーランド、
ゴールデンリングがついてねえや
There aren't any golden rings on this merry-go-round.
And so, he became a prince...
彼はこうして王子になった
王様のいないこの国で
in this country where kings don't even exist.
夜は封印
戸惑い混じれば終わる
迷い出すぐらいならいっそ
わ     け
理由も捨てよう
また夢に溺れる
不確かに続いてく未来
まだ君を許せる
意味を知れる
耳を澄ますための夜
その理由を真似て変われる
君の呼吸を知るために
未来の根を切っても構わない